Guide to the James H. Karales photographs, 1953-2006 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- Manuscripts and Printed Materials Series, 1955-2002 and undated, bulk 1965-2002, (2 boxes and 5 oversize folders)
  - Biographical Information Subseries, 2000-2002 and undated, (6 folders)
    - Essay on teaching by Karales, undated (Box 32)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation application, supporting documentation, and curriculum vita, undated (Box 32)
    - Who's Who In America entry submission, undated (Box 32)
  - Civil Rights Subseries, 1965 and undated, (7 folders)
    - Negative envelopes for job 2309, 1965 Mar. 26-May 18 (Box 32)
    - "Black emergence," unidentified publication, undated (Box 32)
    - Image for book, "60s book/Selma march," unidentified publication, undated (Box 32)
    - "A march for integration in Selma, Alabama," unidentified publication, undated (Box 32)
    - March from Selma image for exhibit, untitled and undated (Box 32)
    - Photo cropping guide for March from Selma image, untitled and undated (Box 32)
    - Photocopy of March from Selma image, untitled and undated (Box 32)
  - Civil Rights/Martin Luther King, Jr. Subseries, undated, (2 folders)
    - Photocopies of contact sheets and photos, undated (Box 32)
    - Photocopies of images, undated (Box 32)
  - Clippings Subseries, 1955-2002, (10 folders)
    - Floats, bands and marchers thrill sesqui parade spectators, The Canton Repository, 1955 Aug. 21 (Box 32)
    - Eyes on the prize: the prize is civil rights, Dial, 1987 Jan. (Box 32)
    - Woodstock Times, 1997 Sept. 18 (Box 32)
    - Boxer, Sarah, "Photography review: the night side of black and white," The New York Times, 1999 July 23 (Box 32)
    - Goldberg, Vicki, photography review: Beyond a famous shot, the art of a lifetime, The New York Times, 1999 July 23 (Box 32)
      (3 copies)
    - William Gedney exhibit review, exhibit at Gallery 292, Village Voice, 1999 July 27 (Box 32)
    - Photography exhibit review, exhibit at Howard Greenberg Gallery, Village Voice, 1999 July 28 - Aug. 3 (Box 32)
    - Photography exhibit review, exhibit at Greenberg, The New Yorker, 1999 Aug. 2 (Box 32)
    - William Gedney exhibit review, exhibit at Gallery 292, The New Yorker, 1999 Aug. 2 (Box 32)
    - Westchester Magazine, 2002 (Box 32)
    - Rye Magazine, 2009 (Box 32)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, undated (Box 32)
  - Clippings Subseries (oversize), 1987-1997, (4 folders)
    - Reynolds, Barbara, TV series teaches how a movement is made, USA Today, 1987 Jan. 21 (Box 29)
    - Goldberg, Vicki, photography review: Remembering the faces in the Civil Rights struggle, "The New York Times, 1994 July 17 (Box 29)
    - Zimmerman, Kevin, PBS 25th anniversary: Making room for quality time: upscale, loyal viewership remains intact; solid fare plays key role in success, unknown publication, 1994 Mar. 14-20 (Box 31)
    - Norklun, Kathi, Looks like America: classic images from Look magazine at Coffey Gallery, Woodstock Times, 1997 Sept. 18
  - Correspondence Subseries, 1971-1999 and undated, (8 folders)
    Folders of letters and notes mostly concerning permissions for publication of images. In some cases, Karales was not the direct recipient of the letters, but was copied on the exchange.
    - Smith, Claire, Harold Ober Associates, 1971 July 20 (Box 32)
    - Maxey, David, 1971 July 23 and undated
    - Zerby, Donna P., Corporate Communications, Scott, 1971 Nov. 18
    - Matthews, Margaret, Reader's Digest, 1982 Mar. 15
    - Durland, Steven, General Manager, Astro Artz, Inc., 1983 Aug. 22
    - Boston Publishing Company, 1984 Mar.-1985 Aug.
    - Courtwright, David, Professor of History, University of North Florida, 1999 Jan. 25
    - Carlos from Michigan, undated
  - Logging Subseries, 1961 and undated, (2 folders)
    - Smith, Jerome B., Supervisor, Visual Information, Weyerhaeuser Company, Correspondence, 1961 Oct. 4 (Box 32)
    - Weyerhaeuser Company, exhibit, undated
      Includes photo captions printed on company letter-head.
  - Lower East Side Subseries, 1969 and undated, (4 folders)
    - Negative envelopes for job 5264, 1969 Aug. 4-Dec. 8 (Box 32)
    - Excerpts from interview with Father Bruce Ritter, undated
    - "An explosion of aggression," unidentified publication, undated
    - Photocopies of images, undated
  - Martin Luther King, Jr. Subseries, 1983 and undated, (3 folders)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr. from Montgomery to Memphis, exhibit pamphlet, New York State Museum, 1983 Jan. 15 (Box 32)
    - King: a photobiography of Martin Luther King, Jr., exhibit pamphlet, Viking Studio, undated
    - Unidentified publication, undated
  - Martin Luther King, Jr. Subseries (oversize), 1999
    - Pamphlet, National Historic Site, National Park Service, U.S. Department of the Interior, 1999 (Box 30)
  - Other Printed Materials Subseries, 1972-1999 and undated, (11 folders)
    - Photocopies of slides of New York City, Pine, New York, Croton, New York, and Townshend, Vermont, 1972-1980 (Box 32)
    - James H. Karales: an adventure in photojournalism, exhibit at Rizzoli Gallery, N.Y., New York, 1980 May 29-June 30 (Box 32)
    - Images from SEI Corporation annual report (images taken by Karales), 1987 (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous images, 1993 Oct. 20 and undated (Box 32)
    - "Look again: photojournalism by Look magazine staffers: Charlotte Brooks, Phillip Harrington, James H. Karales, Tony Vaccaro," exhibit at the Coffey Gallery, Kingston, New York, 1997 Sept. 6-Oct. 1 (Box 32)
    - Witness (exhibit), 1999 June 25-July 31 (Box 32)
    - Map of New York and New Jersey, undated (Box 32)
    - 1965 (Columbia record cover), undated (Box 32)
    - Picture credits and acknowledgments, unknown publication, undated (Box 32)
    - Sixties (photocopy of poster/pamphlet), undated (Box 32)
    - Special pre-schooling for 5-year-olds with learning disabilities, undated (Box 32)
  - Other Printed Materials Subseries (oversize), 1983
    - Exhibit poster, New York State Museum, 1983 (Box 28)
  - Published Works Subseries (oversize), 1955-1965 and undated, (5 folders)
    - Karales, James H., Ohio sub hunters, Cleveland Plain Dealer Pictorial Magazine, 1955 Aug. 21, (2 copies) (Box 31)
    - Castan, Sam and James H. Karales, Vietnam, Look, 1965 Apr. 6 (Box 31)
    - Castan, Sam and James H. Karales, Saigon: stained pearl of the orient, Look, 1966 May 17 (Box 31)
      (2 copies)
    - Spike, Robert W., Our churches' sin against the Negro, Look, 1965 May 18 (Box 31)
    - Castan, Sam and James H. Karales, The new New York: victims of welfare, unknown publication, undated
  - Published Works Subseries, 1964-2000 and undated, (18 folders)
    - Brooks, Charlotte, Look Editorial Preview, 1964 Jan. 28 and Inside Look, 1967 Feb. 3 (Box 32)
    - [Outer space ghost story], Look, 1966 Feb. 22 (Box 32)
    - 1966 All-American cities, Look Editorial Preview, 1967 Apr. 18 (Box 32)
    - Chapter 2: What teaching is like, unknown publication, 1979 June 14 (Box 32)
    - Negroes-history/March to Selma, American Heritage, 1982 June/July (Box 32)
    - The children's crusade saves the day and Bloody Sunday in Selma, unknown publications, 1997 Apr. 24 (Box 32)
    - Photocopies of images from the civil rights series, unknown publication, 2000 Feb. 17 (Box 32)
    - Chapter 6: African Americans, the struggle for civil rights, unknown publication, undated (Box 32)
    - Chapter 32: Leadership of the 1960s, unknown publication, undated (Box 32)
    - Dulli, five poems, unknown publication, undated (Box 32)
    - Helping with drug misuse, unknown publication, undated (Box 32)
    - Images from book on career options, unknown publication, undated (Box 32)
    - Images from copy about payroll, undated (Box 32)
    - The march from Selma to Montgomery finally begins, Martin Luther King, Jr., undated (Box 32)
    - Marchers, Selma to Montgomery, Alabama, 1965, unknown publicationundated (Box 32)
    - [Moral therapy in Gheel, Belgium], unknown publication, undated (Box 32)
    - Pembroke, Herbert, 10.4 civil rights demonstration, unknown publication, undated (Box 32)
    - Williams, Juan, Eyes on the prize: America's civil rights years, 1954-1965, New York: Viking Penguin Inc., undated (Box 32)
  - Published Works Subseries (oversize), 1965
    - Look magazine, 1965 Apr. 6, "Vietnam" (Box 30)
  - Rendville, Ohio Subseries, undated, (3 folders)
    - Exhibit materials, undated, (2 folders) (Box 33)
    - Research notes on Rendville, Ohio and Perry County, Ohio, undated (Box 33)
  - Vietnam Subseries, 1963-1968 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 33)
    - Negative envelopes from jobs 1610 and 2735, 1963 Nov. 18-1968 Dec. 10 (Box 33)
    - Photocopies of contact sheets and prints, undated (Box 33)
- Audiovisual Materials Series, 2000-2006 and undated, (3 folders)
  A variety of recordings and still images: a video (VHS) of photographs by Karales; a CD-R of an interview conducted with Karales on September 16, 2000; an audiocassette of remarks made by Sam Stephenson at an opening of a Karales exhibit at Duke, April 2005; and a CD-R from 2006 with JPEG files of 31 photos from the Vietnam series.
  - Audiovisual materials, 2000-2006 and undated (Box 33)